Now I want to take a quick moment to give you a flyby of five different ways that llms are used commercially,
잠시 시간을 내서 llms의 상업적 사용법을 다섯 가지로 나눠서 저공비행해
and you probably know of 50 more, but it's good to take a moment to look at them and to be food for
보겠습니다 아마 50가지도 더 있겠지만 잠시 살펴보고 llms의 다른 상업적
thought for you to consider other commercial applications of llms.
응용법을 고려해 볼 가치가 있다고 생각해요
And while we're doing this, also be thinking about how you would assess the right model for these different
이걸 하는 동안 이런 다양한 문제들에 맞는 모델을 어떻게 평가할지
problems, using the kinds of leaderboards and the arena that we've already talked about.
생각해 보세요 리더보드와 이미 얘기한 경기장을 이용해서요
The first one I wanted to show you is a company called Harvey, which uses llms in the field of law,
첫 번째로 하비라는 회사를 소개할게요 법률 분야의 llms를 사용하는 회사인데
and you can read through their site, but it gives products for lawyers that will do things like answering
이 사이트에서 변호사들에게 제공하는 상품이 있어요 법률 관련 질문에 대답하는
questions on on law, what what is a claim of disloyalty?
용도죠 불충의 주장이 무엇일까요?
And I believe it also does things like looking through legal documents to find key terms and the like.
법률 문서를 뒤져서 핵심 용어를 찾는 일도 할 거예요
It makes so much sense to be applying llms to the field of law that it's a no brainer.
llms를 법학 분야에 적용하는 건 당연한 일이에요
It's a classic example of needing to use language and nuance and apply it to difficult business Challenges.
언어와 뉘앙스를 활용해 어려운 비즈니스 챌린지에 적용해야 하는 전형적인 예죠
Here's another.
또 있어요
And this is near and dear to my heart because this is my day job.
이건 제게 아주 소중한 일이에요 이게 제 본업이거든요
This is Nebula.
이건 네뷸라예요
Uh, Nebula io, which is using llms to apply to the world of talent and recruitment, helping managers
네뷸라 이오라는 회사인데 llms를 이용해 인재 채용의 세계에 지원해서 매니저들이 훌륭한 후보를
to hire and engage with great candidates.
고용하고 엮이게 돕는 곳이죠
But it's also helping people to explore and understand where they can be most satisfied and successful.
하지만 동시에 사람들이 탐구하고 이해하도록 돕죠 자신이 가장 만족하고 성공할 수 있는 곳을요
Using Llms to understand the content of people's careers.
Lms를 이용해 사람들의 커리어를 이해하는 거죠
Again, it's the kind of use case that makes so much sense.
다시 말하지만 이런 게 아주 합리적인 사용 사례죠
This one is one that I find particularly annoying.
이게 특히 거슬려요
I am, uh, upset by this particular company.
이 회사 때문에 화가 나요
Blooper AI um bloop, which is a platform that ports.
실수 인공지능 움 블룹 포트가 되는 플랫폼이죠
Legacy code into Java.
Java로 레거시 코드를 보내죠
And the reason that I find this, uh, galling is because I wish I had thought of it.
이 상황이 짜증 나는 이유는 내가 왜 그 생각을 못했을까요?
It's such a great idea.
정말 좋은 생각이에요
It's such an obvious idea.
너무 뻔한 아이디어잖아요
Obviously.
당연하죠
Brilliant.
훌륭해요
As soon as I heard it, I thought, oh, that's a great idea.
그 말을 듣자마자 좋은 생각이라고 생각했어요
Uh, so of course there is tons of COBOL code out there and other legacy code.
코볼 관련 코드가 아주 많아요 다른 레거시 코드도 많고요
And it's it's a huge challenge for large corporations to figure out how to maintain this code, as people
대기업이 이 코드를 유지하는 법을 알아내는 건 큰 도전입니다 사람들이 코볼 언어
increasingly don't want to work with languages like COBOL.
같은 걸 점점 꺼리기 때문이죠
And there's a lot of legacy code that people can't read and understand.
사람들이 읽고 이해할 수 없는 레거시 코드가 많아요
Um, and it's such a perfect use case for coding models that can learn different programming languages
코딩 모델에 있어서는 완벽한 사용 예로 다른 프로그래밍 언어를 배울 수 있고 한 언어에서
and then can use that to port from one language to another, and presumably can do things like adding
다른 언어로 포트를 할 수 있고 주석 추가나 테스트 케이스 같은
in comments and test cases and everything else.
것도 할 수 있을 것 같아요
Um, so, uh, yes, it's uh, dang it.
네, 맞아요, 젠장
They've they've obviously, uh, really struck on a fantastic idea.
정말 환상적인 아이디어를 떠올린 것 같아요
Uh, I think this is a great looking product from a Y Combinator backed company.
와이 컴비네이터 백업 사 제품으로 아주 좋아 보여요
And, uh, yes, congratulations to to bloop.
네, 축하해요, 블룹
And I love the name bloop.
블룹이란 이름도 좋아요
Uh, on on less uh, memorable name would be, uh, this Salesforce product Salesforce's Einstein copilot
덜 인상적인 이름에는 이 세일즈포스 제품을 추천할게요 세일즈포스의 아인슈타인 부조종사
health actions Quite a mouthful, but I will say that aside from the slightly clunky name, the product
건강 행동 꽤 길지만 이름만 좀 투박할 뿐 제품 자체는 말이 된다고
itself again is one of those ones that's like, oh yes, that makes sense.
생각할 만한 제품이에요
Uh, a sort of, uh, dashboard that can be used by healthcare practitioners, for example, to do things
일종의 대시보드인데 의료 종사자가 사용할 수 있습니다 의료 관리자를 위한 요약
like summarize for a care coordinator, the outcomes of a medical appointment, saving presumably tons
같은 걸 할 때 쓰죠 진료 예약 결과를 보면 아마 시간이 많이 절약될 겁니다 그리고 일어난
of time, and giving this kind of very compelling summary of what happened, uh, which for all we know,
일을 아주 인상적으로 요약할 수 있죠 너무 쉬워서 그라디오 앱이 될
could be a Gradio app because that easy.
수도 있어요
Uh, but it's probably something Salesforce, uh, but it's such a good use case makes a lot of sense.
세일즈포스 관련 문제일 수도 있지만 아주 유용한 사용 사례예요
And obviously, uh, no doubt Salesforce is going to do really well with that product.
세일즈포스는 그 제품으로 분명히 성공할 거예요
And then I came across Khan.
그러다 칸을 만났어요
Mingo Khan.
밍고 칸이에요
Yes.
네
I think it's probably how it's pronounced conmigo.
콘미고라고 발음하는 게 맞을 거예요
Um, uh, which is, uh, the Khan Academy.
칸 아카데미라는 곳이죠
Uh, presumably, uh, with a mingo at the end of it.
아마 맨 끝에는 밍고가 있을 거예요
Uh, and this is an LLM based platform to be a companion for teachers, learners and parents.
교사, 학습자, 부모를 위한 동반자로서 LLM 기반 플랫폼이죠
And what a great idea again.
정말 좋은 생각이었어요
And the Khan Academy is a obviously a fabulous resource, and I'm sure that this is something that this
칸 아카데미는 분명 훌륭한 자원이고 이 해결책은 분명히
solution is something that will be immensely valuable.
엄청난 가치가 있을 거예요
And the application of LMS to education is something which is again a no brainer, absolute no brainer.
LMS 응용 프로그램은 생각할 것도 없어요
So across these different examples, law, talent, coding, the medical field and education, you can
법, 인재, 코딩, 의학, 교육 등 다양한 예시를 보면 LMS가 이 모든 제품에
see the impact that LMS will be able to make in each of these products.
어떤 영향을 미칠지 알 수 있죠
And I'm sure you have many other examples yourself, but hopefully, as I say, this has given you food
물론 다른 예도 많이 있겠지만 부디 이번 사례가 생각할 거리를 제공했길 바랍니다
for thought and also interesting to think about how you would be assessing different models that you
또한 이런 문제를 해결하기 위해 여러분이 선택한 다양한 모델을 어떻게 평가할지 생각해 보는 것도
would pick to solve any of these problems.
흥미로웠으면 해요
To state the obvious, of course, for this one, no doubt we'd be looking at the medical LMS leaderboard
당연한 걸 짚고 넘어가자면 이 강의에서는 의료용 LMS leaderboard와 포옹하는
and hugging face, and here we'd be looking at many of the coding metrics, not just human eval for
얼굴이 보이겠죠 그리고 코딩 지표도 많이 볼 겁니다 파이썬에 대한 인간 평가뿐
Python, but the coding metrics for other languages too.
아니라 다른 언어의 코딩 지표도 볼 거예요
Okay, with that we will go over to wrap up.
좋아요, 이제 마무리하러 가죠